

Ricky Valentine Oswald

Nationality: British Date of birth: 08/06/1986

Caree Company Service Servic

Website: https://rvo.pythonanywhere.com

• Home: Flat 1 204 Perowne Way, PO369NX Sandown (United Kingdom)

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A lifelong computer enthusiast with over 8 years industry experience

I have been interested in computers and technology since childhood, writing my first programs with Microsoft's QBasic when I was 12 years old. I went on to study at College and University focusing on games programming, which I employed in several successful roles, and expanded into back-end web development for national healthcare. In recent years my focus has shifted away from games and I've spent much of my spare time with GNU/Linux and other free software projects, gaining appreciation of technical, community, and licencing aspects of development. Most recently I have been studying Assembly x86_64, C and Kernel/OS development. Structured languages such as C++ and the Object-Oriented approach are definitely my comfort area, but I like to think I am language and system agnostic.

DIGITAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: C/C++, C#, Java, Python, ASM x86_64 / Web Development: Django/Python, Bootstrap, jQuery, PHP, SOAP, Restful APIs / Game Development: AdobeAir, XNA, DirectX, Blender / Operating Systems: Linux, Windows, macOS / Dev Environments: VSCode, Visual Studio, Eclipse, VIM/Shell, Git, SVN

WORK EXPERIENCE

Grounds Maintenance Operative

John O'Connor [01/05/2023 – 01/08/2024]

City: Ryde | Country: United Kingdom

Backend Developer

Prime Carers [01/10/2020 – 01/02/2023]

City: Sandown | Country: United Kingdom

- RESTful API Integrations with Aircall, Drip, Slack and Stripe
- Back-end architecture of the Prime Carers web platform
- Full-stack development with Django, Bootstrap and jQuery

Kitchen Porter

Liz Earle & Dairyman's Daughter [01/01/2018 - 01/08/2020]

City: Arreton | Country: United Kingdom

Web Application Developer

Pinnacle Systems Management [01/01/2016 - 01/01/2018]

City: Newport | Country: United Kingdom

- API Development, using PHP and SOAP, of Electronic NHS Discharge Referrals and NHS 111 Emergency Repeat Prescriptions
- Creating and maintaining SSL certificates
- Liaising with and on-boarding hospitals and pharmacies to the PharmOutcomes web platform

Managing Director

Monkeypants Studio [01/01/2014 - 01/01/2016]

City: Sandown | Country: United Kingdom

- Unity game development with C#, Blender, and GIMP
- Managed collaboration with artists and musicians
- Secured funding and mentorship for business foundation and development

Software Developer

Oak Games [01/01/2012 - 01/01/2014]

City: Ryde | Country: United Kingdom

- Multi-platform game development using ActionScript and AdobeAir
- Native Android development of brain trainer software
- Chart dominance on Amazon Kindle eReader App Store (discontinued)

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Computer Games Programming

Huddersfield University [01/07/2008 – 01/01/2012]

City: Huddersfield | Country: United Kingdom | Website: https://www.hud.ac.uk/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 5

BTEC Level 3 IT Practitoners

EDEXCEL [01/07/2003 - 01/06/2004]

City: Newport | Country: United Kingdom | Website: https://iwcollege.ac.uk/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 5

Level 2 Diploma for IT Users

City & Guilds [01/07/2002 – 01/06/2003]

City: Newport | Country: United Kingdom | Website: https://iwcollege.ac.uk/ | Level in EQF: EQF level 4

C&G Certificate Visual Basic

City & Guilds [01/07/2001 – 01/06/2002]

City: Newport | Country: United Kingdom | Level in EQF: EQF level 2

GCSE Science, English, Maths

Sandown High School [01/07/1999 - 01/06/2002]

City: Sandown | Country: United Kingdom | Level in EQF: EQF level 3

REFERENCES

Mr. James Bowlder - PrimeCarers - james@primecarers.co.uk - 0203 369 3624

Mr. Dave Walker - Oak Games - dave@oakgames.co.uk - 07706 869574

Dr. Duke Gledhill - Huddersfield University - d.gledhill@hud.ac.uk - 01484 472758